So hot...
暑い
どうして　ここは　こんなに乾いているんだろう
Why is it so dry here?
本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
This is the story of a man. A sad, sad man.
これは　ある一人の哀れな男の物語
诸
神字幕组
剥がれ落ちた夢 澱む幻
The dream that's fallen away
and the stagnant illusion
もう この世界を見放した者さえ
The words embrace even the ones
who have abandoned this world
包み込む言葉
刹那に消えゆく
Disappearing instantly
共に囚われの明日を取り戻そう
Let's take back the imprisoned
tomorrow together
何もかも失くしても
Even if we lose everything
最期の審議の日まで　ずっと
Until the judgment day
Keep on blooming proudly like flowers
花のように強く咲き誇れ
絶望のオト　拾い集めて
Pick up the sounds of despair
永久に奏でる　ストレインに変える
Play it forever and change it into strain
I'll stick around, clinging onto the subtle light
僅かなヒカリ　すがりついても
留まるから
届けたい　残らず
I want to convey it until there's nothing left
第27话 世界之力
与
Episode 25
Tranquility, Indolence, and a Tale of Despair
懒觉
和
绝望的故事
The Age of Paradise's end.
楽園時代の末期
愚劣で愚鈍で浅はかな人間に絶望したオルントーラは
Disappointed in the foolish,
dimwitted, shallow humans,
七つの戦機を持つ　七体の懲罰天使を地上に放ちました
Orntorra unleashed upon the world
seven angels of punishment,
bearing seven war-machines.
Then, prior to their arrival, he announced
he would be destroying the world.
そして　やがて来たるべき時
地上を滅ぼすと宣言したのです
I saw it!
私は見た　一人の英雄が
A hero will save the world from
the Beasts of the Final Chapter!
この世界を終章の獣から救うの
必要なのは　十万人の戦士　七つの戦機
To assure victory, he requires
100,000 soldiers,
seven war-machines,
and the books of 100,000 soldiers!
そして　十万人の戦士の「本」である
我らの「本」を透明の髪の英雄に捧げよ
Let us offer our books to the
hero with transparent hair!
彼の名はルルタ　ルルタ＝クーザンクーナ
His name is Ruruta! Ruruta Coozancoona!
Ruruta! Ruruta! Ruruta!
ルルタ　ルルタ　ルルタ…
Ruruta! Are the magic rights running rampant?
ルルタ　皆の魔法権利が暴れておるのか
Ruruta... You cannot handle ninety-nine books.
ルルタよ　九十九冊などさすがに無理があったんのか
I will be strong.
僕は強くなる
ルルタ
Ruruta!
「本」に込められているのは　魔法権利だけではない
Magic rights are not stored
alone within those books.
一冊一冊に込められた　切ない思いを
Each book also contains its author's despair.
世界は彼らのものだ
The world belongs to them!
A minstrel? That's rich!
歌い人　笑わせる
ただ歌うだけで　魔法権利も持たず
You're nothing but a lowly dog
without magic rights!
Unable even to die for Ruruta,
all you can do is sing!
ルルタのために死ぬこともできぬ
下劣な雌犬が
Her name is Nieniu.
彼女はニーニウ
歌い人と呼ばれる　人々の心を癒やす歌を歌う一族
She comes from a tribe of minstrels who
use song to heal people's hearts.
彼女はその　最後の生き残りでした
She was their last surviving member.
He's crying again.
また　あの子が泣いてる
I'm scared. I'm scared!
怖い　怖いよ
怖がらない
Don't be scared. Fear is for the weak.
怖いのは強くないから
待っていて
Hold on!
I can't take it anymore.
僕にはもう耐えられない
終章の獣が近付いてくる
The Beasts of the Final Chapter are nearing.
僕は倒す
I will defeat them.
I'm scared. I can't slay them!
怖い　倒せっこない
もうすぐだから
I'm almost there.
Myself, the others... Everyone will die.
僕も　皆も　誰も彼も殺されてしまう
I will emerge victorious!
僕は勝つ
We'll be slaughtered...
殺される
Hold out. I'm nearly there...
もうすぐ　私はあなたに…
Let's die.
死のう
Death's the only way. There's no other escape.
死ぬしかない
死ぬしかないんだ
Wait! No!
待って　駄目
駄目よ　死んでは駄目
No... You mustn't die!
Who are you talking to?
誰と話をしている
Huh?
え？
You are...
あな…たは
透明の髪
You... You're Ruruta Coozancoona,
the one with transparent hair, right?
ルルタ＝クーザンクーナ
あなただったのですね
女　なぜここに来た
Girl, why have you come here?
苦痛に耐え兼ね　恐怖に戦いている少年がいるからです
I followed a boy who shivered in fear,
unable to endure the pain.
Ruruta, I came to save you.
ルルタ　私はあなたを助けるためにやってきました
僕を助ける
Save me? Don't be foolish!
馬鹿な
僕は皆を助けるために存在する
I exist to save humanity.
守るために存在するんだ
I exist to protect them.
そんな僕が助けられるなど
You think you could save me?
Tell me. Am I truly Ruruta?
教えてくれ　僕は本当にルルタなのか
Ruruta feels no fear. Ruruta never loses the way.
ルルタは恐れない　ルルタは迷わない　ルルタは挫けず
Ruruta is impregnable. Ruruta is indomitable.
ルルタは決して負けない　そのはずじゃないのか
Isn't that how it should be?
教えてくれ　僕は本当にルルタなのか
Tell me. Am I truly Ruruta?
だったら　なぜこんなに辛いんだ
If I am, then why is life so difficult?
なぜ　こんなに怖いんだ
Why do I tremble with fear?
They all believe in me,
皆が僕を　信じている
nary a doubt in their minds.
何の　疑いもなく
ルルタが救ってくれる
Ruruta will save us all!
全てルルタが救ってくれる
Ruruta will save everything!
If I lose focus, falling to defeat,
I'll never be forgiven.
僕には　負けることも　迷うことすら　許されていない
I will forgive you.
私は　あなたを許します
終章の獣に　勝てなくても？
Even if I lose to the Beasts
of the Final Chapter?
ええ　あなたを許します
Yes. I will forgive you.
Look at your face, so deep in thought.
物思いに沈む横顔　素敵じゃない
How wonderful...
I guess you had enough in you
to tear Chacoly to pieces, huh?
チャコリーが骨抜きにされるだけあるわね
チャコリー
Chacoly? That creepy little girl?
あの薄気味悪いの娘か
僕に愛を説いた　無謀な娘
She spoke to me of love.
A foolhardy girl...
そう　そして絶望し　壊れて
Agreed. And then she died in despair.
蓄音機みたいに　胸糞悪いラブソング歌い続けてさ
Like a gramophone, she kept repeating
some nauseating love song.
Stop.
やめろ
やめねば　今ここで殺そう
Stop. Or I'll kill you here and now.
じゃ　やーめた
Fine. I stopped.
あたしはあんたみたいな小便臭い餓鬼　趣味じゃないわ
Anyway, I'm not into little boys
like you, who piss their pants.
You know what, I changed my mind.
I am going to kill you.
やはり気が変わった
今　ここで殺そう
ハミュッツが　死んだ
Hamyuts... is dead?
You've always been like that.
お前は　いつもそうだ
いつも俺の前を走って
Always running away from me...
Never waiting... for me.
決して　俺を待ってくれない
マット＝アラスト
Mattalast!
くそ
Damn it!
You also need not resist fate any longer.
君も　もう運命に抗わなくていいんだ
Sweet dreams, Enlike Bishile.
お休み　エンリケ＝ビスハイル
焦らないで　もうすぐだから
Don't panic. I'm almost there, Nieniu.
ニーニウ
なぜ
Why? You should be able to
handle that level of flame.
この程度の炎は 簡単に制御できていたはず
今まで
Till now, a supreme vocation,
ルルタ様を支えておりましたのは
to be the world's saving grace,
has supported Lord Ruruta.
自らは世界の救世主であるという絶大な使命感でございます
逃げることも　恐れることも許されない
His conviction that to lose his way or
to feel fear would not be forgiven...
という気持ちでございます
世界を救わねばならぬという　強迫観念でございま
His obsessive belief that he
must save the world...
Ruruta! Ruruta! Ruruta!
His obsessive belief that he
must save the world...
ルルタ　ルルタ　ルルタ…
Ruruta! Ruruta! Ruruta!
If that faith wavers, loss of
his power is inevitable.
それが弱まれば　力を失うことは必然
This is the only way.
こうするしかないんだ
Otherwise, I will be unable
to protect the world.
こうしなければ
世界は守れない
御免なさい　ルルタ
I'm sorry, Ruruta.
Why are you apologizing?
なぜ君が謝る
Because I forgave you,
you lost your power
私が　あなたを許したせいで
あなたは力を失い　ますます苦しむことになった
and continue to suffer.
抵抗してくれなければ　すぐに終わってしまう
Don't fight it, and it'll be over soon.
言い残すことはないのか
Any final words?
一つ　頼みがあります
I have one request.
何でも言ってくれ
Name anything. I'll do whatever you ask.
君の言うなら　僕は何だってする
ずっと　元気でいてください
Stay, always, in high spirits.
ルルタ
Ruruta?
Ruruta...
私は　この世界を守りたい
I want to protect the world.
救世主でもない　君が
Even though you aren't its savior?
ええ　私は　この世界を愛している
Yes, because I love it.
私を生かしてくれた世界だもの
It's the world that allowed me to survive,
あなたに出会えた世界だもの
the world that allowed me to meet you.
そうか　そうだったんだ
Yes. That's it!
Huh?
どうして君を殺す必要がある
Why must I kill you?
君は世界を愛している
You love the world.
君を守ることは　君の愛する世界を守ることだ
To protect you is to protect
that world that you love.
世界は　君と僕のものだ
The world belongs to you and me.
For your sake, I shall become the world's
true savior, Ruruta Coozancoona!
君のために　僕は本当の救世主
ルルタ＝クーザンクーナになってみせる
ルルタ
Ruruta, it seems you've once again
wakened as the savior.
救世主としての自覚を取り戻されたようですね
僕はもう　迷うことはない
I shall never waver again.
素晴らしい
How stupendous.
ヴーエキサルがルルタに飲ませたもの
The drink Vooekisal served to Ruruta
それは　虚構抹殺杯「アーガックス」
was out of none other than the
fantasy-slaughter grail Argax.
ルルタ　ルルタ　ルルタ…
Ruruta! Ruruta! Ruruta!
The end of days is finally upon us.
とうとう来た　最後の日だ
僕は行く
I shall go forth!
追憶の戦器を手に　終章の獣を倒し
To save the world from the
Beasts of the Final Chapter,
この世界を救うために
I wield the war-machines of the past!
ルルタは恐れない
Ruruta feels no fear!
ルルタは諦めない
Ruruta will not give up!
ルルタは逃げず
Ruruta will not run away!
ルルタは決して負けない
Ruruta will not be defeated!
In a new era, ridden of the Gods,
また会おう
神の消えた　新たな時代に
we shall meet again!
Yeah!
Infinite Beasts of the Final
Chapter stand before me.
終章の獣は無限に撒きてる
獣たちの核でなる存在があるはず
There must be a central being unifying them.
ルルタは　終章の獣を操る
Ruruta found the core controlling
the Beasts of the Final Chapter.
その存在を見付け
I will save the world!
世界を…
お見事でございました
Fantastic work, Lord Ruruta.
ルルタ様
お読みになりますか
Care to read it?
こ…れは…
Th-This...
な、なぜ
Why... did I... forget you...
僕は　君を　忘れ…た
ニーニウ
Nieniu!
助けて　ルルタ　ルルタ
Save me, Ruruta! Ruruta!
傑作だ
Get a load of this. The dumb girl
still hasn't figured it out.
まだ何も分かっておらんぞ
このくそ虫は
お前は見捨てられたのだ
You were tossed to the curb...
ニーニウと言う悪魔から目覚め　救世主として目覚めた
By Ruruta, after he awoke,
from the nightmare you brought
to him, as the world's savior!
ルルタに
潰れてしまった
My voice is crushed.
もう歌えない
I can no longer sing...
ルルタが愛してくれた　私の歌
... Sing my song, which Ruruta loved.
私は…
I...
そこで死んで行け
Die in that pile of crap,
糞便にまみれ　たった一人でなあ
all by your lonesome!
I wish... that I had... never born...
私は　生まれてこなければよかった
Nieniu, wake up. Nieniu.
ニーニウ　目覚めなさい
ニーニウ
あなたは？
Who are you?
I am the God of the future, Orntorra.
私は未来神--オルントーラ
The time of ruin has finally
descended upon the world.
この世界に滅びの時がやってきました
滅びの？
Ruin?
Fear not. In endings come beginnings.
案ずることはありません
終わりは始まり
この世界を滅ぼし　新たな楽園を築き上げるのです
I shall create a new paradise in the
wake of this world's destruction.
A new paradise?
新たな楽園を？
あなたが生きたのは694番目の世界
You lived in the 694th world.
The God of the past, Bantorra,
過去神--バントーラ
the God of the present, Towitorra,
現代神--トーイトーラ
そして私は
and I, have created hundreds of paradises.
「楽園」と呼べる世界をなんども作り上げてきました
しかし人間は　同じ過ちを繰り返す
However, humanity continues
to make the same mistakes.
虐げ　欺き　奪い
They persecute, they cheat, they steal.
「楽園」に悲しみの花を咲かせ
They plant the flowers of
sadness in paradise itself.
駄目
No! Such a world should not exist!
こんな世界を奪っちゃいけない
Destroying it does not mean it is over.
滅ぼすことは　終わりではありません
失敗した世界を新たな「楽園」へと作り替える
We recreate failed worlds as paradise again.
Is that... so?
そう…だったんだ
So I shouldn't be singing
a song of healing.
私がするべきことは　癒しの歌を歌うことじゃなく
I should destroy the world.
世界を　滅ぼすこと？
Ruruta loved the world and me...
That is the only way to heal it.
それだけが　私を愛し　ルルタが愛したこの世界を
癒すことになる
ふん　これでルルタも…
So now Ruruta, too...
うん？
That's...
あれは？
ニーニウ
Nieniu...
忘れていた
I forgot all about it.
世界を守りたかったのは
I wanted to save the world
because I wanted to protect
愛するニーニウと　彼女の幸せを守りたかったからだ
the happiness of Nieniu, whom I loved.
それなのに…
Yet, I...
ルルタ様
Lord Ruruta.
ニーニウを幸せにするには　これしかない
This is the only way to make Nieniu happy.
その娘はもうはや　人の心を持っておりません
I'm afraid she no longer
possesses a human heart.
She wished for destruction
and lived in destruction.
滅びを望み　滅びに生きる
滅びの意志そのもの
She embodied willful destruction.
For you to grant her happiness
is absolutely impossible.
それは幸せにするなど　如何にあなた様でも絶対に不可能
Even so...
それでも
これしかないんだ
This is the only way.
そして
And then, on the fifth morn after
he left his imperial capital...
ルルタが王都を飛び立ってから　五日目の朝
ルルタだ
It's Ruruta!
ルルタが帰ってきたぞ
Ruruta has returned!
終章の獣を遣っ付けてくれた
He defeated the Beasts of the Final Chapter!
ルルタ　ルルタ　ルルタ…
Ruruta! Ruruta!
Ruruta!
Ruruta! Ruruta! Ruruta! Ruruta! Ruru...
ルルタが武装司書と神溺教団と作った理由は
So is that why Ruruta created
the Armed Librarians
これだったか
and the Church of Drowning in God's Grace?
ああ　ニーニウに幸せな「本」を与え続けようとしたんだ
Yes. He kept trying to give books
of happiness to Nieniu,
彼女を救うために
in hopes of saving her. However...
だがそれは…
泣いているのか　アルマ
Are you crying, Alme?
分からないよ
I don't understand.
分からないが
But though I don't understand,
I know that this world cannot be saved.
この世は救われないってことだけは分かった
そうだな
You're right. It's impossible to
save Ruruta from despair.
彼を　ルルタをこの絶望から救い出すのは不可能だ
Just excellent, Ruruta!
素晴らしいですぞ　ルルタ
これが滅びの勝利
This is the triumph of ruin.
非の打ちどころはない
It is absolutely spotless.
私の思うまま　私の願うままだ
It's exactly as I'd thought it would
be, exactly as I asked for.
くそ爺
Screw you, old man!
また「本」を食ったのか
He consumes another book?
全てを終わらせる前だというのに
Although the end is nigh,
その貪欲さもまた
he remains ever so gluttonous.
ようこそ
Welcome, newly arrived book!
新しき「本」よ　ようこそ天国へ
Welcome to Heaven!
これは　轢弾
A stone pellet?
あいつが
It's her?
行かなくちゃ
I must go.
コリオ＝トニス
Colio Tonies.
Go where?
行くってどこへ
ここはどこまで行ったって　ルルタの腹の中
This entire world now exists in Ruruta's belly!
おい
Hey!
「仮想臓腑」で何か
Something's in the nonentity entrails...
I haven't consumed that woman's book.
あの女の「本」を食らってはいない
だが…
And yet...
ニーニウ
Nieniu.
やっぱり
Seems you couldn't kill me, after all.
あんたには殺せなかったみたいねえ
ねえ
So that's why you must survive, Matt.
だから　マット
あんたは生きて
Survive...
あんたは…生きて
A feather in the air captures the dream
It's swimming in the darkness,
pretending to be flying
Let's ask the sad blue sky for the answer
Bang on the closing door (Forcefully)
Sneak out and greet for one last time
"Who did you keep on search for?"
I'm lost for words and don't know the answer
Because of the broken love
Now I've lost everything
An angel will no longer come
Dominant Space
動きを止めた数多な「本」に
New pages are written into the countless books
Atonement,
紡がれて行く新たなページ
that had been stopped dead in their tracks.
世界を救うために
To save the world.
Atonement, Delusion,
そして　輝ける第二の死を迎えるために
And to experience a spectacular second death.
赎罪与疑惑和书中的书
Atonement, Delusion, and Books Within Books
And to experience a spectacular second death.